## **Sheikh Ahmed**

New York, NY (347) 933-8355

SSAHME21@GMAIL.COM

https://github.com/ArcRiseGen132

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sheikhahmed21/

### **Summary**

I'm an energetic, team player who helps people through technology and communication; my passion for technology and education has no bounds. I have both COMPTIA A+ and SEC+ certifications, with the end goal being cybersecurity for cloud services. I am experienced in computer breakdown and repair as well as hardware troubleshooting and am currently attending Kenzie Academy for a full-stack software engineering certification.

#### Skills

COMPTIA A+, Sec+ - JavaScript/ HTML5/ CSS - Microsoft Office
 Programming - Coding - MERN Stack
 Multitasking - Visual Studio Code - NoSQL
 Enthusiastic - Peer Code Review - NPM/Yarn

## Experience

#### Freelance Field Service Technician

June 2018 - December 2020

- Upgrading all components of computer hardware for consumers to have easier use.
- Troubleshooting, break/fix, hard ware, software, operating systems, and network connection along with internet protocols.
- Independent computer consultant for Desktop and Laptop repair, maintenance and upkeep.
- Repair, maintenance, and troubleshoot PC computers including break/fix operations.
- Responsible for all desktop, laptop break/fix issues

### **Self, New York** - Private Tutor

August 2018 - Present

- Prepare high school students for the SAT, PSAT, and New York Regents exams
- Design curriculum to address weaknesses of students and create lesson plans to remedy said weaknesses
- Adapt to the needs of students and teach in various ways in order to reach academic goals
- Continuously update parents regarding the performance of the students

## Smart Academia, New York - Lead Tutor/IT Support

October 2012 – May 2018

- Taught 2<sup>nd</sup> to 12<sup>th</sup> grade students in preparation for Common Core, SHSAT, SAT, and Regents
- Recommended, designed, and wrote test prep packages for students
- Trained new tutors regarding teaching methods, computer maintenance, and client relations
- Performed computer maintenance, including network hardware, software troubleshooting, break/fix printer troubleshooting, and part replacements
- Enable passwords on computers to prevent non-permitted downloads and installations.

# **Academic Projects (Hands on experience)**

Create Connect Four in JavaScript (Project Manager, working with 3 others)

Bug Fixing in JavaScript using MERN Stack for a custom application for Kenzie Academy

Coding search bar functions, password requirements/verification, and login fields.

Write code for basic shopping page with user functionality.

### Education

Kenzie Academy, Indianapolis – Full-Stack Software *Engineering MERN* (Oct. 29<sup>th</sup>, 2021) CUNY Hunter College, New York – *B.A Media Studies (August 2012 – January 2016)* High School for Health Professions and Human Services - *Advanced Regents Diploma* (2011)